<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NeuroDesk – Neurodesktop</title><link>https://neurodesk.github.io/docs/neurodesktop/</link><description>Recent content in Neurodesktop on NeuroDesk</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://neurodesk.github.io/docs/neurodesktop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Getting Started</title><link>https://neurodesk.github.io/docs/neurodesktop/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neurodesk.github.io/docs/neurodesktop/getting-started/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: What's next?</title><link>https://neurodesk.github.io/docs/neurodesktop/whats-next/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neurodesk.github.io/docs/neurodesktop/whats-next/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Now that you’ve installed and launched neurodesktop, you should see a virtual desktop environment in your browser, which might look something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://neurodesk.github.io/Desktop.png" alt="desktop" title="desktop">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this linux desktop environment, you can access the menu, launch programs, write analysis code, use version control software (i.e. git) and develop analysis pipelines as though you were on your own computer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="release">Release&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Keep a note of the release date of the container image that you installed. Regardless of what operating system you installed neurodesktop into, the release date would have been at the end of the &lt;em>docker run&lt;/em> command:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://neurodesk.github.io/version.png" alt="version" title="version">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We regularly update neurodesktop to make sure it’s running well and has up-to-date software. You can check the &lt;a href="https://neurodesk.github.io/docs/neurodesktop/release-history/">Release History&lt;/a> page for details of previous releases. If you’d like to update your container at any time, simply switch out the release number for the version you would like. If you’ve finished working on an analysis pipeline and would like to share it with others, you can point them toward the stable release number that you worked in. That way anyone, on any computer around the world can replicate your analysis pipeline in the exact same computing environment that you developed it in.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="video-tutorial">Video tutorial&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Click &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JLv_5fycugw">here&lt;/a> to watch a 2 minute tutorial video from OHBM 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-access-files-from-your-host-computer">How to access files from your Host computer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>-v C:/neurodesktop:/neurodesktop&lt;/code> part of the docker command links the directory &amp;ldquo;neurodesktop&amp;rdquo; on the &amp;ldquo;C drive&amp;rdquo; of your Windows computer to the directory &lt;code>/neurodesktop&lt;/code> inside the Desktop environment. Everything you store in there will be available inside neurodesktop and on the host computer. You can also mount additional directories by adding another -v parameter set (e.g. &lt;code>-v D:/moredata:/data&lt;/code>) - this will mount the directory moredata from your D drive to &lt;code>/data&lt;/code> inside neurodesktop.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-launchdownload-applications">How to launch/download applications&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Click on the Launcher icon in bottom-left corner and navigate to the &amp;ldquo;Neurodesktop&amp;rdquo; menu, then select the application and version you wish to launch. If it is the first time you launch the application, it will be downloaded to your desktop environment. The application is ready to use when the &amp;ldquo;Singularity&amp;gt;&amp;rdquo; prompt appears in the terminal window that opens. If you chose in the menu the GUI of the application (e.g., fsleyesGUI 6.0.3), it will open automatically. If you chose that application itself (e.g., fsl 6.0.3), a terminal window will open, and you can use it to run any of the utilities packaged with the application, including the graphical utilities (e.g., typing &amp;ldquo;fsl&amp;rdquo; to run FSL&amp;rsquo;s main menu).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: What's in the box?</title><link>https://neurodesk.github.io/docs/neurodesktop/whatsinthebox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neurodesk.github.io/docs/neurodesktop/whatsinthebox/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Neurodesktop comes with the essential software required for neuroimaging data analysis pre-installed. Each release is built with the most recent version of these packages available at the build date. Some example packages include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Visual Studio Code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Emacs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gedit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Vim&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lua&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Git&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lmod&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nipype&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rsync&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Singularity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GraphVis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Imagemagic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Htop&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Firefox&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nextcloud client&lt;/li>
&lt;li>OpenSSH client&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The neurodesktop environment is built to be light and fast to download and start-up. A number of additional programs are therefore available to use in the container, and will be downloaded when they are first used. A list of these additional packages can be found &lt;a href="https://github.com/NeuroDesk/neurodesk/blob/master/cvmfs/log.txt">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Troubleshooting</title><link>https://neurodesk.github.io/docs/neurodesktop/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neurodesk.github.io/docs/neurodesktop/troubleshooting/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Neurodesk is an open-source project that is always evolving. If you are experiencing an issue not listed here, please open a &lt;a href="https://github.com/NeuroDesk/neurodesk.github.io/issues">new issue&lt;/a>, so that we can aim to solve it and update our help documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To ask questions or suggest new features, &lt;a href="https://github.com/NeuroDesk/neurodesk.github.io/discussions">join the discussion&lt;/a> on github.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="windows-users-wsl-not-installed-properly">Windows users: WSL not installed properly&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Docker engine relies on the Windows subsystem for Linux (&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install-win10">WSL&lt;/a>) to run on a windows machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note&lt;/h4>
We recommend the &lt;em>manual&lt;/em> install instructions, as the simplified install requires an upgrade to a preview build of Windows that may be unstable.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>If WSL is properly installed, the &lt;em>Resources&lt;/em> tab of the Docker settings should look something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://neurodesk.github.io/Docker_WSL_correct.png" alt="Docker_WSL_correct" title="Docker_WSL_correct">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, if WSL is missing or incorrectly configured, the &lt;em>Resources&lt;/em> tab of the Docker settings may look something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://neurodesk.github.io/Docker_WSL_incorrect.png" alt="Docker_WSL_incorrect" title="Docker_WSL_incorrect">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If this is the case, follow the manual install instructions to install &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install-win10">WSL 2&lt;/a> (including installation of Ubuntu through Microsoft Store).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Release History</title><link>https://neurodesk.github.io/docs/neurodesktop/release-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neurodesk.github.io/docs/neurodesktop/release-history/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Coming Soon&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>